let questions=
[
 {
        "numb": 81,
        "question": "How many strokes make up the operating cycle of a four-stroke engine?",
        "answer": "Four",
        "options": ["Two", "Three", "Four", "Six"]
    },
    {
        "numb": 82,
        "question": "How does a turbocharger get its power?",
        "answer": "From the exhaust stream turbine",
        "options": ["From the engine-driven air compressor", "From the exhaust stream turbine", "From the propeller", "From the fuel injection system"]
    },
    {
        "numb": 83,
        "question": "What is the altitude limit at which an aircraft with normally aspirated engines reaches its service ceiling?",
        "answer": "Where the manifold pressure is insufficient",
        "options": ["Where the oxygen level is insufficient", "Where the manifold pressure is insufficient", "Where the engine power decreases", "Where the aircraft stalls"]
    },
    {
        "numb": 84,
        "question": "How do superchargers or turbochargers affect an aircraft's service ceiling?",
        "answer": "They increase it",
        "options": ["They decrease it", "They have no effect on it", "They increase it", "They vary depending on the altitude"]
    },
    {
        "numb": 85,
        "question": "What causes the oil temperature to rise?",
        "answer": "Reduced oil quantity",
        "options": ["Reduced oil quantity", "Increased airflow", "Rich mixture", "Decreased engine RPM"]
    },
    {
        "numb": 86,
        "question": "Where can operating characteristics such as expected performance be found?",
        "answer": "Pilot Operating Handbook or Type Certificate Data Sheet",
        "options": ["Fuel system manual", "Engine maintenance guide", "Pilot Operating Handbook or Type Certificate Data Sheet", "Airframe maintenance manual"]
    },
    {
        "numb": 87,
        "question": "What is the primary function of superchargers and turbochargers in aircraft engines?",
        "answer": "To increase the density of intake air to boost horsepower",
        "options": ["To regulate fuel flow", "To increase the density of intake air to boost horsepower", "To cool down the engine", "To reduce exhaust emissions"]
    },
    {
        "numb": 88,
        "question": "What is the key difference between superchargers and turbochargers?",
        "answer": "Superchargers are engine-driven, while turbochargers are exhaust-driven.",
        "options": ["Superchargers are exhaust-driven, while turbochargers are engine-driven.", "Superchargers are engine-driven, while turbochargers are exhaust-driven.", "Superchargers use fuel injection, while turbochargers use a carburetor.", "Superchargers are mechanical, while turbochargers are electrical."]
    },
    {
        "numb": 89,
        "question": "What is the purpose of a manifold pressure gauge in an aircraft with superchargers or turbochargers?",
        "answer": "To monitor the pressure within the engine's intake manifold",
        "options": ["To measure engine RPM", "To display fuel pressure", "To monitor the pressure within the engine's intake manifold", "To measure the exhaust temperature"]
    },
    {
        "numb": 90,
        "question": "How do superchargers or turbochargers affect an aircraft's service ceiling?",
        "answer": "They increase the service ceiling.",
        "options": ["They decrease the service ceiling.", "They have no effect on the service ceiling.", "They increase the service ceiling.", "They regulate the temperature of the cabin."]
    },
    {
        "numb": 91,
        "question": "What is the function of a tachometer in an aircraft engine?",
        "answer": "To measure the engine's RPM",
        "options": [
            "To measure the engine's oil pressure",
            "To measure the engine's RPM",
            "To measure the fuel flow rate",
            "To measure the altitude of the aircraft"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 92,
        "question": "What is the purpose of a Hobbs meter in an aircraft?",
        "answer": "To record the time the engine is running",
        "options": [
            "To measure engine RPM",
            "To measure the engine's oil pressure",
            "To record the time the engine is running",
            "To record the altitude of the aircraft"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 93,
        "question": "What is the function of a wastegate in turbocharged engines?",
        "answer": "To prevent the exhaust pressure from exceeding the maximum allowable manifold pressure",
        "options": [
            "To regulate the flow of fuel into the engine",
            "To divert exhaust gases to drive the compressor",
            "To prevent the exhaust pressure from exceeding the maximum allowable manifold pressure",
            "To increase the density of intake air"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 94,
        "question": "What is the primary advantage of gas turbine engines over traditional reciprocating engines?",
        "answer": "They have a higher power-to-weight ratio.",
        "options": [
            "They are quieter.",
            "They are cheaper to manufacture.",
            "They have a higher power-to-weight ratio.",
            "They have lower fuel consumption."
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 95,
        "question": "What is \"tach time\" typically used for?",
        "answer": "Recording engine run time for maintenance inspections",
        "options": [
            "Calculating fuel consumption",
            "Measuring engine oil quantity",
            "Recording engine run time for maintenance inspections",
            "Monitoring engine temperature"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 96,
        "question": "What are the main components of an aircraft turbine engine?",
        "answer": "Air inlet, compressor, combustion chambers, turbine section, exhaust",
        "options": [
            "Air inlet, carburetor, piston, exhaust pipe",
            "Air inlet, compressor, combustion chambers, turbine section, exhaust",
            "Carburetor, spark plug, crankshaft, propeller",
            "Fuel injector, intake manifold, cylinder head, exhaust manifold"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 97,
        "question": "What is the relationship between heat and thrust in turbine engines?",
        "answer": "More heat equals more thrust",
        "options": [
            "Heat decreases thrust",
            "Heat has no effect on thrust",
            "More heat equals more thrust",
            "More heat equals less thrust"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 98,
        "question": "How many types of compressors are there for turbine engines?",
        "answer": "Three",
        "options": [
            "One",
            "Two",
            "Three",
            "Four"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 99,
        "question": "How does a centrifugal flow engine compress air?",
        "answer": "By accelerating air outward perpendicular to the longitudinal axis of the machine",
        "options": [
            "By accelerating air inward perpendicular to the longitudinal axis of the machine",
            "By accelerating air outward perpendicular to the longitudinal axis of the machine",
            "By moving air parallel to the longitudinal axis",
            "By rotating airfoils"
        ]
    },               
    {
        "numb": 100,
        "question": "What produces thrust in an aircraft engine?",
        "answer": "Accelerating exhaust gases",
        "options": [
            "Compressing air",
            "Igniting fuel-air mixture",
            "Accelerating exhaust gases",
            "Cooling the engine"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 101,
        "question": "How many sections does a turbojet engine consist of?",
        "answer": "Four",
        "options": [
            "Two",
            "Three",
            "Four",
            "Five"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 102,
        "question": "What drives the turbine in a turbojet engine?",
        "answer": "Expanding air",
        "options": [
            "Combustion chamber",
            "Expanding air",
            "Inlet air",
            "Exhaust gases"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 103,
        "question": "What are turbojet engines limited in?",
        "answer": "Range and endurance",
        "options": [
            "Range and endurance",
            "Power and speed",
            "Altitude and temperature",
            "Torque and RPM"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 104,
        "question": "What is the primary function of a turboprop engine?",
        "answer": "Driving a propeller",
        "options": [
            "Generating electricity",
            "Driving a propeller",
            "Cooling the engine",
            "Compressing air"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 105,
        "question": "What determines the type of aircraft turbine engine?",
        "answer": "The path the air takes through the engine and how power is produced",
        "options": [
            "The size of the aircraft",
            "The path the air takes through the engine and how power is produced",
            "The manufacturer of the engine",
            "The altitude at which the aircraft operates"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 106,
        "question": "What are the five major components of an aircraft turbine engine?",
        "answer": "Inlet duct, compressor, combustion chamber, turbine, exhaust assembly",
        "options": [
            "Inlet duct, compressor, combustion chamber, turbine, exhaust pipe",
            "Inlet duct, combustion chamber, gearbox, turbine, exhaust assembly",
            "Inlet duct, compressor, combustion chamber, turbine, exhaust assembly",
            "Inlet duct, radiator, turbine, compressor, exhaust assembly"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 107,
        "question": "How is compression of inlet air achieved in a centrifugal flow engine?",
        "answer": "By accelerating air outward perpendicular to the longitudinal axis of the machine",
        "options": [
            "By accelerating air outward perpendicular to the longitudinal axis of the machine",
            "By rotating and stationary airfoils moving air parallel to the longitudinal axis",
            "By using both centrifugal and axial flow compressors",
            "By accelerating air parallel to the longitudinal axis of the machine"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 108,
        "question": "What is the purpose of the power turbine in a turboprop engine?",
        "answer": "To drive the reduction gear assembly",
        "options": [
            "To compress inlet air",
            "To drive the reduction gear assembly",
            "To cool the engine",
            "To measure torsional deflection"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 109,
        "question": "What is the function of a torque-meter assembly in a turboprop engine?",
        "answer": "To measure the horsepower produced by the engine",
        "options": [
            "To measure the horsepower produced by the engine",
            "To control the airflow through the engine",
            "To adjust the bypass airflow",
            "To measure the temperature of the exhaust gases"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 110,
        "question": "How do turbofan engines differ from turbojet engines?",
        "answer": "Turbofans have a shorter takeoff distance and produce more thrust during climb-out.",
        "options": [
            "Turbofans have a longer takeoff distance and produce less thrust during climb-out.",
            "Turbofans have a shorter takeoff distance and produce more thrust during climb-out.",
            "Turbofans have a longer takeoff distance and produce more thrust during climb-out.",
            "Turbofans have a shorter takeoff distance and produce less thrust during climb-out."
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 111,
        "question": "What is the primary advantage of high-bypass turbofan engines?",
        "answer": "They are more efficient for commercial aircraft.",
        "options": [
            "They are more suitable for high-speed aircraft.",
            "They are more efficient for commercial aircraft.",
            "They produce less noise during takeoff.",
            "They provide higher climb-out thrust."
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 112,
        "question": "What does adjusting the bypass airflow in turbofan engines achieve?",
        "answer": "It increases cruise speed and reduces fuel consumption.",
        "options": [
            "It increases cruise speed and reduces fuel consumption.",
            "It decreases cruise speed and increases fuel consumption.",
            "It increases engine cooling and reduces noise.",
            "It decreases engine efficiency and increases emissions."
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 113,
        "question": "Which type of runway is intended for aircraft using instrument approach procedures?",
        "answer": "Instrument Runway",
        "options": [
            "Non-Precision Runway (NP)",
            "Precision Runway (P)",
            "Non-Instrument Runway (NI)",
            "Instrument Runway"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 114,
        "question": "What equipment is used for horizontal navigation in the Instrument Landing System (ILS)?",
        "answer": "Ground Localizer (LLZ) Antenna",
        "options": [
            "Ground Glide Path (GP) Antenna",
            "Marker Beacons",
            "Ground Localizer (LLZ) Antenna",
            "Airborne LLZ antenna"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 115,
        "question": "What is the purpose of Marker Beacons in the ILS?",
        "answer": "To enable the pilot to cross-check the aircraft's height",
        "options": [
            "To provide vertical navigation",
            "To enable the pilot to cross-check the aircraft's height",
            "To provide lateral guidance",
            "To serve as visual aiming points for landing aircraft"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 116,
        "question": "What is the function of the ground localizer antenna in the Instrument Landing System (ILS)?",
        "answer": "Providing guidance for aircraft to align with the runway centerline",
        "options": [
            "Transmitting UHF signals vertically",
            "Transmitting VHF signals horizontally",
            "Providing guidance for aircraft to descend",
            "Providing guidance for aircraft to align with the runway centerline"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 117,
        "question": "Where are the localizer and glide path antennas located on the aircraft?",
        "answer": "Nose",
        "options": [
            "Wings",
            "Tail",
            "Nose",
            "Fuselage"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 118,
        "question": "How do the localizer and glide path antennas guide the pilot?",
        "answer": "By energizing needles on the ILS indicator",
        "options": [
            "By activating the throttle",
            "By providing audio instructions",
            "By energizing needles on the ILS indicator",
            "By displaying visual cues on the cockpit windshield"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 119,
        "question": "What is the function of the glide path antenna in the ILS?",
        "answer": "Transmitting UHF signals vertically",
        "options": [
            "Transmitting VHF signals horizontally",
            "Transmitting UHF signals vertically",
            "Providing lateral guidance",
            "Providing speed adjustments"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 120,
        "question": "What color is the cockpit indicator for the outer marker?",
        "answer": "Blue",
        "options": [
            "Blue",
            "Red",
            "White",
            "Green"
        ]
    }


]